Hello.
Welcome back.
And this lesson, we are going to see how to configure our SDM 32 you art for interrupt mode.
So what I'm going to do is create a pin out of created a new project, as you can see, after years
to collect a pin out.
And then the other time we use that, you are Temotu to this time less use.
You are too much of one.
And remember, you, art module one is no hasn't got the, um, the V1 capability.
If you using your automotive one or your nuclear board, you wouldn't be able to view it on Terra too.
You would require the extend or you are to us be convertor in order to view it.
It just happens that our You are module two is connected to the debugger which allows us to view it.
So this time we're going to use module one and this time we would use this opportunity to try to receive
a function as well.
And what we're going to do is we're going to tie the transmit and the receive pins of our microcontroller
such that we can create a loop back.
The data we send through the transmit, we receive it through, they receive a pin.
And this will verify that we've configured both our Rex and T x.
So come to connectivity over here and then I'll select you at one.
And once I've selected it, I'll open this.
And then now enable it as asynchronous mode.
And then this will show that pins involved here.
It's P A ten and P in nine.
So to create a U.
A loop back.
We know this is the R x receive.
And is the T expen.
So what we can do is take a jumper wire, connect to P eight nine and P a 10.
So we connect a pin here such that what is transmitted from P in I will be received from P A 10.
And we can verify that what we transmit is received.
Right.
Next we go to a clock certains.
I'm going to go to the clock set in here and then I'm going to select it.
As I as the source from this multiplex up over here.
Once that is done, I'm going to make sure my you are to pass is 16 megahertz so that those with the
F one FS Air Force, your one would just use the default settings or hit enter here.
And then everything will be adjusted accordingly.
Next, we go back to the PIN and configuration tab to continue our configuration.
I'll come to systems for you here.
I'll click my you at one, you know, expand from here.
Let's see.
Yes.
To be expanded.
Okay.
And over here.
OK, keep everything the same.
We want to receive and transmit the other part.
We wanted the same.
But because we said we'll be use and interrupt, we have to enable global interrupt for the U.
The USA.
So click over here to care to enable global interrupt.
Now I can go ahead and generate the code.
Come over here, generate code.
I'll give this a name you art underscore.
Interrupt.
And then also to change over here.
SDM 32 cube idi e.
And once that is done or click over here to generate.
So this is whole project of cleaned up, a bit of taken out most of the comments over here.
And then you can inspect the generated code.
It's almost the same as the one we saw for our you are to pull in.
The only differences on, um.
An interrupt handler was created in the underscore I don't see followed by here because we enabled global
interrupt.
So if you open estimated to four X X underscore, I don't see you feed C D.
Do you not interrupt handler included here.
As you can see, you use that one I RCU handler.
Right.
Okay, so we'll come over here.
Well we have to do is start out.
Were you at transmit.
Receive which interrupt.
And then we implement the interrupt callback whenever we use in the library.
We know when you use interrupt.
You've got to implement the callback function.
So.
Right to find the callback function.
We know the trick.
We go to our Triva file and then we find the, um, the type of callback we want to do.
We want a callback for data received complete or we want a callback for data transfer complete.
We want a callback for data have received complete meaning if half of the reception is complete.
All of that is there.
And we can find that out by going to the driver.
So go to drive us over here.
How driver, the source and what we're looking for is that you art or use that dot c file over here
to return.
You asked to see a double click this.
And we know the, um, the callbacks always start with the underscore week keyword.
So we can simply search the control F to open the fine window.
You press control plus F and then you type on the score week and then you start looking for it by hitting
enter to go to the next one.
So this is the um, transmit complete callback.
And there is trust me, to have complete callback.
We looking for transmit complete.
We need this.
We're gonna implement one callback for transmit complete.
And another one for transmit half complete.
There should be a callback, a single callback for both transmit complete and receive such that it's
gonna be you at T X are x complete callback.
But we are using t x separately and RACC separately.
So let's get to our X version.
O continue by looking.
So this is the R X complete.
I'll copy this as well.
Right.
So I'm just gonna clean this up.
We don't need the content in here.
We don't need a content in here as well.
And then the week keyword here can be eliminated.
Okay.
So for this experiment, we went to create two buffers, just like we saw earlier in the earlier example,
we had a buffer, which was basically, um, an array of characters.
And then, um, the buffer had a content halo from Cuba, Max.
This time, we simply going to create an array of numbers.
And this we would send from one buffer and expect to receive it in another buffer using our T X are
X looped back because we are going to use a jumper wire to connect our T X line to the R X line, such
that when we send from T X, we expect to receive an X and we expect what we receive to be available
in a while are X buffer.
So I'm going to come over here and create two arrays.
I'll see you in eight.
And this Quartey and then I'll call this T x buffer.
And it's gonna be an array of size 10.
And over here, I'm just going to put numbers.
Start off by saying, um, 10, 20, 30, 40, 50, 60, 70, 80, 90 and 100 like this.
And then over here, I'm going to see you integrate.
And there's Corti.
And this is going to be the ah X buffer.
This is going to be the receive buffer.
And it's a size of 10.
But this one is empty.
This we expect to find data inside this when we run our code.
Okay.
And remember, the callback function is just the function for doing something.
Basically, if you have something you want to do when data is received, you do it over here and over
here, do something as well.
But over here, because we don't have anything special to do, we can simply increment a counter variable
or come here and create you.
X3 to underscore T accord is our X counter.
And then I have another one called X counter.
These are global variables.
And then in the Eriks callback, I just increment the ERIKS counter.
Rick's account plus plus.
Like this.
And then over here to X.com, two plus plus.
And we will observe these counter variables in the expressions window like this.
Okay.
But you can do any elaborate stuff.
You can pass the on the data.
Perhaps if you receive data, you will not pass it through an algorithm such as delete the comma process,
CSP file, et cetera.
You can do it in the callbacks and um.
Yeah, depending on the type of data.
If it's not text then it's actual signal such as um maybe ADC values, you may want to clean it up,
et cetera.
All of that you can deal with using callbacks.
Okay.
So once that, uh, once we've implemented our callbacks, we can go ahead and start the, um, the
ADC stats, the you ought I should say.
So let's start o u.
Are we going to set out where you are to receive interrupt.
We're going to see all on the scroll you out.
That's that's the name of the function.
And you can find this in the, um, the driver fault, which is that you are but see all the um the
whole reference manual.
So this is you are to receive on the score.
Eighty four, interrupt, receive, use and interrupt.
And the first argument is the outrage of the you are to handle which is you are one over here and then
the buffer for the received data.
Where do you want to store what you received.
Want to store it.
You know.
What did we call it.
Quantity over here.
Eric's buffer.
I'll copy this R x buffer over here.
And then the next one is going to be the size, which is ten.
So pass this over here like this, following this.
The next one is going to be the transmit.
So over here, receive which interrupt.
Now transmit.
Oh.
On a scale you art
transmit on the school I.T..
And then the first document is the U to handle U R to one.
The second one is the transmit which is T X buffer.
And then the size is 10.
So we're going to take what is in T X buffer, which is this content, and then transmit that.
And because we're gonna connect a jumper wire, we're going to connect our ex ante X line using a jumper
wire.
What is transmitted or what is sent through the transmitter we received on the receiver pin and stored
in the receiver or our X buffer.
So now we can go ahead and arm and build our project.
But before we do that, we have to create the loop back.
We spoke about what this was helping over here.
We said we're going to connect our X and T X lines.
So we've got to connect P 18 to P in line if you're using the Discovery Port.
It's written on it.
So, you know, way to look at your P it and MPLX nine, which I use in a nuclear.
You've got to check the actual pin out, not what is written.
What is written is based on the art we know.
P note.
So this is a new clue.
Actual pin out and then know we're looking for P in nine MPLX 10.
So this is P in nine over here.
This is P nine and this is P a ten.
So we've got a connect to jump a wire from here.
One leg of the jumper wire here and the other one here.
And this would create a loop back connecting T, X and I.
Right.
Click over here to build my project.
It's Putin, it's pretty successfully.
Click here to go to the debug.
So what we want to do is check put our ERIKS buffer to our live expressions and see if data is received
when we're right, when we run our code.
We can also check out our extensive X counter to see is going to send us once.
Oh, yeah.
Let's see.
I'm when I remove this, this is from a previous project.
Remove all and I'm going to come over here are X buffa.
Remember our X barflies empty.
No X barflies.
The one with the data.
But we've created a loop back.
We've connected Ericsson t x so we expect to receive at our X.
Okay.
And then I'm going to take my R X counter as well or other over it.
I'm copying by pressing control see.
And then we can see T X can't control see to copy double click control V to paste over here.
And then I'm going to put a breakpoint at my wild one loop.
Remember we are using interrupt so we don't um.
We don't have to implement anything in here.
I'm simply going to double click here to put a break point here.
Then I'm going to click here to run the code.
And the Tehran and it stopped over here.
We can take a look at it.
Nothing was sent.
Nothing was sent because I can see the Erickson T x counter being, um, zero and zero.
So let's see where the issue is.
So the issue was from my jumper wire.
If your jumper wire is not tightly connected to the P, a nine and a 10.
You might not see the, um, the receiver and transmission happening.
My hands are literally holding in the jumper wise in place.
I'm pressing them so that, yeah.
You know, they're connected.
They're fully connected.
Yeah.
Because in a loose connection would um make this experiment difficult to run.
So as you can see, it's because we run once.
We've already transmitted the data.
You can see our X counter one, anti X counter one, cause there's been a single transmission in a single
reception.
And this is our our X buffer started empty and now he has the content of the T X buffer.
So because of our loop back.
And we can do this again.
Oh, just.
Oh, just, um, stop this.
And then we start again.
And then I'll click over here, come to the bug.
It opened in.
And then I'm just going to remove everything in order to gain.
Because some of them are saying failed to follow it or just remove or not start off by adding our Erich's
buffer to the live expressions window.
And then O.
A war t x counter.
And there no other way.
Ricks counter.
Right.
And we still have our breakpoint here, which is, you know, well, one loop break point is inside
a while, one loop.
Um, so click over here.
Run.
They run.
OK.
I clicked run twice.
And this is what we have.
We have our X buffer, our X buffer with a data.
N t x buffer here one and then our expert for here.
Okay.
Strange.
I don't know what it's because the, um, the breakpoint is in the wall.
One loop that is making it work.
No, but.
Yeah.
This is what it is.
So it is working our loop back.
We've been able to test our our ex ante x but let's test this to get.
I'm gonna put a break points up here and let's see if that would cause any problems for Kubi D e wanna
come out.
I'm gonna stop this and go back into it.
We can run this experiment together and see.
OK.
So I'm going to go back to the debug.
OK, I'm going to take out the break point from here.
You see, the breakpoint is put into 11.
Let me put out a top here.
Let's see when I click here to run.
OK.
Nothing is happening when the breakpoint is at the top, yet nothing happens.
I'm going to take it from here from the wall one line and put it inside a wall, one loop.
So I'm going to put a break point here right now or quick to run.
OK.
So now we know make sure the breakpoint is in the 11 loop.
It doesn't have to be on the line, but in the loop.
Right.
Soon after we've done that.
We can see this, um.
Yeah.
Work the way we expect it to.
Right.
So that's all there is if you have any questions.
Just live in the questions and answers.
Area.
I'll see you later.
Have a nice day.